자막 변환 : ND_현이
Well, there is one thing...
I'd like to ask you.
물감은 어떻게 만드나요?
How do they make that slime
they're always dumping on you?
Oh, well. First,
they take some liquid.
우선 물하고, 기름하고
And then they add some
Jell-O powder and some flour...
양념, 밀가루, 비누를
섞지요, 그리고 부어버려요
and sometimes some soap,
then they dump it all over me.
여보, 어서 준비해요
You better get going, kiddo.
We're gonna be late.
나도 확실히는 모르겠어요
Very interesting.
Is it always green?
녹색인가요?
녹색? 아니, 빨강색이네요
Yeah, it usually is,
but I guess it could be red.
Or it could be blue.
파랑색 같아요
Daddy, telephone.
아빠, 전화!
Thanks, darling.
Hello.
힐디! 아니, 발가락을
채였어, 잠깐만!
Hildy, I'm fine.
I just stubbed my toe.
Hang on one second, will you?
힐디의 전화야
Honey, it's Hildy.
곧 건다고 해요
I'll call her back.
욕탕에 있거든요
She's in the bathroom. She wants
to know what you're wearing.
어떤 옷을 입을 거야?
My black suit.
검정옷!
검정드레스라는군
She's gonna wear her black dress.
Well, it's gonna be business.
You know how those things are.
적당히 입어요
비지니스 파티니까
또 내 화장품 갖고
장난이니!
Ellen, I don't want you
messing with my makeup. I'm late.
빨간 옷을 입겠대
- Is her red dress okay?
- It's perfect.
그럼 됐어요
Did you hear that?
You got it.
들었죠? 이따봐요
Okay, darling.
See you later. Bye.
Oh, man.
만지지 말라고
수천번 얘기했잖아
I told you a million times not
to play with my lipstick, right?
그래도 들으나마나니
원…
So when are you gonna
listen to me, huh?
Silly girl.
Honey, where's my blue suit?
청색 양복을 어디뒀지?
문뒤에 걸려있어요
It's on the back of the door.
원, 세상에…
Oh, shit.
Shit, shit, shit.
세상에…
- Hi, Ellen.
- Hi, Christine.
잘 있었니?
안녕!
- How you doin'?
- Good.
엄마 어디계시니?
- Where's your mom?
- She's in the bathroom.
화장실에요
선물 가져왔어, 보고싶지?
I got you a present.
Wanna see what it is?
맘에 드니?
- Do you like it?
- Uh-huh.
자, 엄마한테 가자
Okay, come on.
Let's go find Mommy.
이번 금요일엔 네가 나와야돼
Hiya, Chuck. How are you? Good to
see you. Can you make it Friday?
- I'm there.
- We need you. We're in the cellar.
자네가 꼭 필요해
Dan, is my hair okay?
머리 스타일 어때요?
멋진데
- You look great.
- I'm serious.
정말이에요?
You're the prettiest woman
in the room, sweetheart.
당신이 여기서 제일 예뻐
Liar.
안녕하세요?
Hiya, Bob. How are you?
와줘서 고마워
내일 회의 건은 미안해
Glad you could make it, Dan.
Sorry about the meeting tomorrow.
I know it's a Saturday,
but we got a real crisis.
주말인줄 알지만
사건이 터졌으니 말야
괜찮아요
내 처 베스에요
I understand. Do you know
my wife Beth? Bob Drimmer.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
초밥을 좋아하겠지?
- Hope you like sushi.
- Love it, Bob.
좋죠, 고마워요
목이 왜 저래요?
- What did he do to his neck?
- He was screwin' his wife.
마누라와 밤일하다 다쳤대
정말요?
- Are you serious?
- Absolutely. You should see his wife.
부인은 들것에 실려 나갔대요
They had to take her out
on a stretcher.
- You guys are bad!
- Do you want champagne?
샴페인 할래요?
- Champagne for everyone.
- With a twist.
Four champagnes over here.
Excuse me. Hi.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
- Jesus!
- Thank you.
Fuck!
- No, thank you.
어떤 행사인데
이렇게 호화판이지?
So, what great cultural event
are we here to celebrate tonight?
- Some exercise manual.
- Not another one.
장수 비결책을 판대
또?
이건 진짜야
This one's different.
사무라이 정신에서 본뜬거래
It's based on
ancient samurai discipline.
Danny, look at this guy nod.
절하는 것도 비결의 하난가?
What is that,
part of the ritual?
Hi there.
- Jesus! If looks could kill.
- Glad you haven't lost your touch.
날 꼬시는군
아직도 젊구나
I think she likes me.
I think she wants me.
날 좋아하나봐
날 원하고 있어!
I think you're batting zero for two,
and I don't wanna know you.
헛물켜다 창피 당하지나 마
- She was undressing me with her eyes.
- You think so? Good luck, pal.
저 눈초리로 날 벗기는군
잘해봐
She had trouble with the buttons.
죽여준다
샴페인 한잔!
- Can I get a champagne, please?
- You got it.
I'm not saying anything.
I'm not even gonna look.
왜 그렇게 노려보셨죠?
너무 심했나요?
Was it that bad?
I was glad I wasn't on the receiving end
of that one. Cheers.
그 눈총을 내가 안받으니
다행이군요
I hate it when guys think
they can come on like that.
전, 무작정 덤벼드는
남자가 싫어요
Jimmy's okay.
짐은 착해요
남자란 실속없이 허세부리죠
He's just a little insecure
like the rest of us.
댄 겔리거라 합니다
- My name is Dan Gallagher.
- Alex Forest.
알렉스 포트레스예요
Nice to meet you.
And what is your connection here?
반가워요, 여긴 어떻게?
출판사의 부편집인이에요
I'm an editor at Robbins and Hart.
And you?
전, 당신 출판사의
변호사입니다
I'm with Miller, Goodman and Hurst.
I do all your legal work.
I haven't seen you around
their office, though.
그런데, 당신은 못 봤는데요
I've just been with them
a couple of weeks.
시작한지 보름됐어요
가봐야겠습니다
- I have to go.
- Is that your wife?
부인이신가요?
빨리 가보세요
Better run along.
만나서 반가웠어요
It was very nice to meet you.
- Give me a break.
- Give you a break? What does this mean?
- How many did you buy?
- What does this mean?
크리스틴, 수고했어
- Thanks again, Christine.
- Anytime, Mrs. Gallagher.
또 부탁하세요
Good night.
할 일이 또 있을텐데?
Aren't you forgetting something?
Quincy, let's hit it, pal.
퀸시, 나가서 누자
You're such a good boy, yes.
아랫배가 시원하지
참아줘서 고맙다
You did such good business.
You're the best, boy.
여보, 오늘만 자겠대요
It's just for tonight, honey.
좋은척 하지마
그래야 깎으니까
When you first see a house,
don't show any interest at all.
- Otherwise you can't negotiate.
- Will you stop worrying about it?
걱정 말아요
엔렌, 또 껌씹는구나!
- Ellen, are you chewing gum again?
- We can't afford it anyway.
돈도 없는데
집을 꼭 사야돼?
Look, there's no harm in looking.
It's just up the road from Mom and Dad.
보기만 하는 거예요
친정에서 가까우니까
사실, 그 점도 꺼림칙해
- Just another reason not to buy it.
- I didn't hear that.
Really nothing to worry about.
We can't afford it anyway.
그래도, 돈만 있으면
그건 문제 안되지
Come on.
Hold on a minute, honey.
그 집을 보지도 않고
벌써부터 걱정이에요?
Let's just not worry about it.
I haven't seen the damn place yet.
I may not even like it.
맘에 안들수도 있잖아요
Ellen, the gum.
껌 뱉어
Thank you.
Come on, Quincy.
퀸시, 빨리와
개는 데려가지마
No, honey. Quincy's
gotta stay here with Daddy.
내가 너무 쓸쓸해져
- Daddy's gonna be all alone.
- Sorry, Quincy.
용변시키는거 잊지마세요
- Don't forget to walk him.
- I promise.
알았어
You promise? Okay.
You have a good meeting.
회의 잘하세요
- See you tomorrow night.
- I love you.
내일밤에 만나
Two times down. Third time up
he looked like a jellyfish.
주말인데, 미안해
안주인 이해시켰지?
Sorry to ruin your weekend. Please
give my apologies to your lovely wife.
걱정마세요
I will.
- So, how you feeling?
- Don't ask.
기분은?
말도마!
알렉스가 대신 온다는군
Henry's out of town, so I asked
Alex Forest to stand in for him.
그여자 왔나?
- Anybody know where she is?
- She's on her way.
기다리는 동안
목에 대해 설명해줘요
Since we got a little time, maybe you
can tell us what happened to your neck.
That's cute. Very cute.
우습기도 하겠다
서류때문에 늦었어요
Sorry I'm late.
I was getting the file.
This is Alex Forest,
our new associate editor.
부편집장인 알렉스야
만나 뵌적 있죠
We've met before.
시작할까?
Okay, can we get started?
Okay, here's the story.
You want to publish a novel...
얘긴 즉슨…
상원의원의 가십을 주제로
소설을 출판하려고 하는데
in which one character is a senator
from New Jersey who's foolin' around.
Now, there's a certain congressman
from Ohio...
문제는 오하이오의 상원의원이
자기를 모델로 삼았다고
고소했어요
who claims the character's based on him
and filed an injunction against this.
그 의원은 대머리지만
주인공은 아니라구
The congressman's bald.
This guy has hair.
They're from different states.
이걸 출판 못하면, 파산이야
If we don't sell those books,
we're screwed.
If I go to court to prove this senator's
not based upon this congressman...
이 고소를 이기려면
우선 진실을 알고 봅시다
then I have to know the truth.
Now...
비밀이 안새는 전제로
작가가 그 의원과 잤나요?
strictly between these walls,
all right...
did the author have an affair
with Mr. Ohio or not?
그랬대요, 또
딴 정치인과도 잤구요
Yeah, she did.
But she also had a lot of affairs
with other politicians.
Any one of them
could make the same claim.
그사람들도 소송걸 수 있어요
그런데, 작가는 모두가
가공인물이라는 거예요
She swears
this character's fictitious.
I just got off the phone with her.
그걸 믿어요?
And you believe her?
네, 믿어요
Yeah, I believe her.
이젠 명백하니
금지령을 풀어
Now that we got that on the table,
what can we do to lift that injunction?
사실이라면
의원에게 접근합시다
If we believe the girl, is there some
way we can get to the congressman?
정치자금으로 돈을 주든지
They take campaign contributions.
Can we buy him off?
뒷조사를 해보든지…
Can we frighten him off? Is there
something in his past we can find?
약점을 캐내야돼
We need to use some leverage.
Give me a break!
Come on.
대만제로군요…
- Is it made in Taiwan?
- These are tough to find.
쓸모없는 거죠
Oh, wait, wait. Here.
We got one.
택시가 오네요
Come on!
술이나 한잔합시다
You wanna go get a drink?
Yeah, I'd love it.
잊지 못할 사건이요?
The strangest case I ever handled?
Well, the truth was
I never actually handled it...
사실은 묘한 경우가 있었죠
but the strangest case
I ever came near to...
엄마의 이혼 변론을
나보고 맡으라고 했죠
was when my parents got divorced
and my mother asked me to represent her.
- 정말이세요?
- 나도 그렇게 물었죠
- You're kidding.
- That's what I said.
"What do you mean?" she told me.
"You know what an asshole the guy is.
그랬더니, 아빠 잘못을 몰라?
넌 29년이나 겪어온 증인이야
You've been a witness to this marriage
for 29 years."
엄마가 그러시는데
믿을 수가 없었죠
Can you believe this?
This is coming from my mother.
- How did you get out of it?
- You can't turn your mother down.
그래서 어쨌어요?
엄마를 거역할순 없잖아요
그래서, 기술적으로 해결했죠
So, I escaped on a technicality.
어떻게요?
- Which was what?
- I didn't practice family law.
가정법은 모른다고 했죠
And it was true, you know,
and she bought it.
사실이었구
엄마도 인정했죠
- 지어낸거죠?
- 그걸 어떻게 지어내요?
- Are you making this up?
- Could I make something up like that?
Waiter.
여기 사람들은
내게 꿈쩍못해요
I've got a lot of pull here.
My favorite restaurant.
- I noticed.
- They know me well.
날 잘 알죠
커피 두잔 줄래요?
Miss. You want a coffee?
Can we have two coffees, please?
Well, I'll tell you, it's...
피실래요?
- You want one?
- No, thank you.
가끔, 변호사는
의사가 된 기분이에요
It's funny being a lawyer.
It's like being a doctor.
모두들, 깊은 비밀을
털어놓거든요
Everybody is telling you
their innermost secrets.
Oh, God.
- 비밀을 지켜줘야 되겠죠
- 물론이죠
You must have to be discreet.
Oh, God, yeah.
당신은?
Are you?
뭐가요?
Am I what?
지키시냐구요
Discreet.
물론, 지키죠
Yes, I'm discreet.
저도요
Me too.
- Can I ask you something?
- What?
물어봐도 될까요?
- Why don't you have a date tonight?
- I did have a date.
토요일인데, 왜
데이트가 없죠?
있었어요
I stood him up.
That was the phone call I made.
취소했죠
아까 전화가 그거예요
Does that make you feel good?
기분 좋으시죠?
It doesn't make me feel bad.
나쁘진 않군요
부인은 어디 있죠?
So, where's your wife?
Where's my wife?
제 처요?
My wife is in the country with
her parents, visiting for the weekend.
주말이라, 친정에 갔어요
그리구, 당신은 딴 여자와
수작하시구요
And you're here with a strange girl
being a naughty boy.
저녁식사 하는 것도
죄가 되나요?
I don't think having dinner
with anybody is a crime.
아직까지는
Not yet.
Will it be?
나중엔?
몰라요, 당신 생각은?
I don't know.
What do you think?
I definitely think
it's gonna be up to you.
무조건 당신에게
달려있다고 봐요
I can't say yet.
I haven't made up my mind.
망설여지는데요
솔직해서 좋군요
At least you're very honest.
우리가 파티에서
눈이 맞은건 분명하고
We were attracted to each other
at the party. That was obvious.
오늘밤, 당신이
자유란 것도 분명해요
You're on your own for the night.
That's also obvious.
우린 성인이에요
We're two adults.
나갑시다
Let's get the check.
- Oh, that was great.
- Thank God.
너무 좋았어요
Are you feeling energetic?
아직 기운 남았어요?
또 뭘하려구?
What do you have in mind?
여기가 어때요?
이 빌딩에서?
You live in this building?
택시를 불러야지
Well, where can I get a cab?
Do you know?
엘리베이터에서 해 본
경험있어요?
- Have you ever done it in an elevator?
- Not recently.
- 기억이 없는데
- 못해봤을 꺼에요
I'll bet you haven't.
어이구, 미안해, 아프지?
I'm sorry, baby.
I'm sorry.
How are you?
여보, 웬일이세요?
Hi. What happened to you?
여태까지도 안오셨으니
I tried you earlier. I'm gonna go...
I guess you're not back yet.
곧 잘꺼니까, 아침에
전화주세요, 안녕
I'm gonna go to bed now,
so call me in the morning. Bye-bye.
댄, 기다렸어
Oh, Dan, darling.
We were expecting you.
죄송합니다, 일 때문에…
I had work to do.
괜찮아, 자네가 그집을
꼭 봤으면 해서…
That's a pity. We really
wanted you to see that house.
다음기회에 보죠
- I'll see it next time.
- Of course. You wanna speak to Beth?
에미 바꿔줄게
Hold on a second.
애기 아빠 전화다!
The phone. It's Dan.
Here you are.
어떻게 되신거에요?
Hello.
What happened to you?
별거아냐, 친구 빌과
밖에서 저녁 먹었어
Hi. Nothing. I just went out
and had dinner with Bill last night.
빌은 잘 있어요?
How is he?
누구? 빌! 그냥 여전해
He's... Bill's Bill,
the same as usual.
아직도 그 여자와…?
Is he still with that girl?
Well, he wasn't last night.
그 여자와 그만 뒀대
말을 잘 안해
I think it's over.
He didn't wanna talk about it.
일은 잘 끝났어요?
So, you getting any work done?
Yeah, I'm working.
진행중이야
There's some of the spaghetti sauce
in the refrigerator if you get hungry.
냉장고에 스파게티가 있어요
배고프면 드세요
잘됐군, 엘렌은?
Great. Okay.
How's Ellen doing?
너무 잘 놀아요
She is having the best time.
I just hope that Dad survives it.
사실은요, 애가
토끼를 원해요
Honey, I don't know
how to tell you this, but...
she wants a rabbit.
토끼는 안돼!
No rabbits!
집안을 노아의 방주로
만들려고 그래?
Jesus Christ! This goddamn family's
turning into Noah's ark.
잘 타일러 봐요
헛 약속하지 말구
I mean, please, give her a kiss,
all right? But no promises.
- All right.
- When are you coming home?
당신 언제 올꺼야?
- Well, it's getting complicated.
- Why's that?
실은, 집문제가 좀
어렵게 됐어요
There's a problem with the house.
팔렸구만
They sold it?
무슨 말씀을?
오후에 보기로 했는데
Very funny. No, we can't get in
to see it until late this afternoon.
늦을것 같아서
하루 더 있을래요
I'm not up to fighting the traffic.
I thought I would come in tomorrow.
아이 학교는?
What about school?
다섯살애가 뭘 덜 배우겠우?
She's only five years old.
What's she going to miss, trigonometry?
Okay, all right. Then I'll see you
when I get home from work.
알겠어, 내일 퇴근후 만나
Okay. See you tomorrow.
그래요, 내일봐요
잘 놀다와요
Okay. Thanks.
Have a good time.
Bye.
눈뜨니 안계시더군요
그건 싫어요
What happened?
I woke up, you weren't here.
I hate that.
메모를 못 봤어요?
You didn't get my note?
What note?
침대 곁에 써놨는데…
I left you a note
right by your bed.
좋아요, 전 하루를
같이 지낼까 했어요
That's nice.
I thought we were gonna
spend the day together.
알렉스, 할일이 너무 많아요
Alex, I got so much work
to do today. I can't.
여하튼 오세요
점심해 놓을께요
Why don't you just come over.
I'll cook us lunch.
I got to take the dog for a walk.
The poor dog has not been out all day.
개도 돌봐야하고
그녀석 용변도…
I gotta take him out.
같이 와요, 멋진 음식을
준비할테니…
Bring the dog. I love animals.
I'm a great cook.
Come on.
정말 못 가요
싫어서가 아니요
Listen. I'd love to, but I can't.
I really can't.
Do what you have to do,
then come over afterwards.
일 끝내고 오세요
점심을 늦게 하죠, 뭐
We can always eat late.
아니면, 여기서 일하시던지
방해안되게 얌전히 있을께요
Or you can work here.
I won't disturb you, I promise.
I'll be a good girl.
정말 고집불통이군
You don't give up, do you?
You just don't give up.
Come on, Quincy.
Help, Quincy.
I got it. I got it.
He's free.
Quincy, cover me.
I'm up. Go deep.
He fires.
Throws.
She got it.
Yes, it's back.
Over the head.
He's got it.
댄!
댄! 들려요?
Dan, can you hear me?
오, 하느님!
Oh, my God.
- You bastard.
- Your face.
나쁜 인간!
놀랬지?
나쁜 장난이었어요
- That was a shitty thing to do.
- I'm sorry. I was just fooling around.
미안, 어쩌나 보려구 그랬어
아빠가 심장마비로
돌아가셨어요
My father died of a heart attack.
일곱 살때, 내 눈앞에서
쓰러지셨죠
I was seven years old.
It happened right in front of me.
미안해, 정말 몰랐어
알았으면 그랬겠어?
Honey, I'm sorry.
Really, I had no idea. If I did,
I never would have done that.
가만있자, 거짓이지?
살아계시지?
What, he didn't die?
He's alive?
Yeah, he's alive and well
and living in Phoenix.
살아계시죠
피닉스에서 살고계세요
이번엔 내가 당했군
You certainly got me,
didn't you?
Let's hear it.
들어봐요!
I hope you like spaghetti.
Specialty of the house.
스파게티는 내 특기예요
Goes with the opera.
오페라와 맞구만
냄새가 좋아
It smells so good.
- Anything else for me to do?
- No, nothing.
도울일은?
없어요, 편하게 계세요
테이프를 바꾸시든가
Just make yourself at home.
You can change the tape.
아냐, 나비부인을
아주 좋아해
No, this is great.
I love Madame Butterfly.
정말? 나도 좋아해요
Really?
It's my favorite opera.
Mine too.
처음 본 오페라였어
First opera I ever saw.
다섯 살때 아빠와 갔었지
My father, he took me to the old Met.
I was five years old.
뜻을 몰랐을 텐데요
Did it make any sense?
대강 알았지, 미 해군병사가
일본여자와 함께 살았는데
I got most of it.
There was this US sailor settin' up
house with this Japanese lady.
끝에 가서는
남자가 떠났어
That was all fine,
but in the final act...
after he left her...
아빠 말씀이, 그녀가 자살한대
난 너무 무서워서…
my father told me
she's gonna kill herself...
and I was terrified.
의자 밑으로 기어들어갔지
I was... I climbed
right underneath the chair.
바로 이 장면!
It's right here.
This is it.
여기야, 여기
웃기지
It's funny.
뭐가요?
What?
아빠가 처음으로
나를 따뜻하게
One of the only times I recall my father
being nice to me when I was a kid...
위로해 주시더라구
comforting me at Madame Butterfly.
What?
뭘 생각해?
What are you thinking about?
I was wondering why is it that all the
interesting guys are always married?
왜 관심있는 남자들은
다 결혼했나 하구요
Maybe that's why you find them
interesting... you can't have them.
소유할수 없으니
더 흥미있는 것 아냐?
결혼한지 얼마됐어요?
How long have you been married?
9년
Nine years.
애는요?
Do you have any kids?
6살된 딸애가 있어
I got a six-year-old girl.
부러워요
Sounds good.
행운이지
I'm lucky.
그런데 왜 바람피죠?
So what are you doing here?
어려운 질문이군
You know how to ask them.
정말 알고 싶어요
I really wanna know.
I had a wonderful time last night.
I'd like to see you again.
어젯밤 참 황홀했고
또 만나고 싶어요
Is that so terrible?
그게 나쁜건가요?
안돼, 앞으론 어려워
No.
I just don't think
it's possible, though.
이상해요, 난
당신에게 빠졌어요
It's really strange.
I feel like I know you already.
I just wanna know where I stand.
내 위치를 알고싶어요
I think you're terrific.
당신은 멋진 여자고…
난 결혼한 몸
But I'm married.
What can I say?
더이상 뭐 있겠어?
내 팔자죠
Just my luck.
Oh, shit.
- 뭘하세요?
- 가봐야돼
- What are you doing?
- I gotta go.
부인은 내일 온다면서요?
I thought you said she wasn't
coming back till tomorrow.
안오지만, 집에서
할 일이 많아
She's not, but I got things to do.
I gotta go home.
난, 이런식은 싫어!
I don't think I like this.
어떤식?
Like what?
The way you run away
after every time we make love.
관계가 끝나면 도망가는거
지금가든 아침에 가든
다를게 없잖아
What difference does it make
whether I leave now or in the morning?
- 가야만 해
- 어쨌든 지금은 못가
- The fact is I gotta go.
- You're not gonna leave now.
왜 이래?
그만두지 못해?
- Come on. Will you stop it?
- I mean it!
Come on. Hey!
알렉스!
왜 난리야?
What's the problem?
I'm sorry.
Jesus Christ.
I mean, let's be reasonable.
제발, 합리적으로
처리하자구
뭐가 합리적이지?
Be reasonable?
What?
고마워, 안녕
전화걸께, 그런거야?
"Thank you. Good-bye.
Don't call me. I'll call you."
당신도 알고 한 짓이야
난 속인거 없어
Look, you knew about me,
all right.
I didn't hide anything.
- 서로 합의했잖아
- 어떤 합의?
- I thought it was understood.
- What was understood?
기회가생겨서 우린 택한거야
The opportunity was there
and we took it.
Come on now.
We are adults, aren't we?
- 우린 어른이야, 안그래?
- 어른이라면?
What's that supposed to mean?
부담없이 즐기는거지
- I thought we'd have a good time.
- No, you didn't.
즐겼다고? 내 생각을
눈꼽만큼이나 해봤어?
You thought you'd have a good time.
You didn't stop to think about me.
That's crazy.
You knew the rules.
미치겠군, 다 그런거잖아?
뭐가 다 그래?
What rules?
Look. I like you.
이봐, 내가 임자가 없다면
널 택했을거야
And if I wasn't with somebody else,
then maybe I'd be with you, but I am.
야! 변명하지마
치사해져!
Please don't justify yourself.
It's pathetic.
If you told me to fuck off,
I'd have more respect for you.
깨끗이 차버리면
존경이라도 할거야
그럼 좋아, 꺼져!
All right then. Fuck off.
이 자식아, 꺼져!
And you get out!
갈게
I'm going.
이리와서 작별인사 해줘요
Why don't you come over here
and say good-bye nicely?
화해해요
Let's be friends.
괜찮아, 괜찮다구
Baby, no.
It's okay.
괴롭혀서 미안해요
Sorry if I upset you.
괜찮아, 정말 괜찮아
It's okay.
It's okay, really.
It's okay. All right.
It's okay now.
손에 땀이 배었군
Your hands are all wet.
오, 하느님! 이리와
Oh, Jesus!
Jesus Christ!
Come here, come here!
Hold on, hold on.
가만있어
Nice and tight.
Hi. Did you just call me?
당신이 전화했었어?
I was in the shower and I heard
the phone. I thought it was you.
샤워중에 전화오길래
당신인줄 알았어
그래. 재미있었어?
So how are you?
Did you have a good day?
Really?
그래? 잘됐구만
That's terrific.
That's really terrific.
너무 좋아하는군
You sound excited.
아냐, 반대안해
단지, 돈이 딸리니까
No, I'm not against the idea.
Don't get me wrong.
It's just the money.
Okay, darling.
그래! 여보, 사랑해
I love you.
Bye.
알렉스
How are you feeling?
기분이 어때?
좋아요
Okay.
가야겠어
I gotta go.
전화해줄래요?
Will you call me sometime?
You don't have to
if you don't want to.
싫으면 안해도 돼요
꼭 할게, 대신
병원에 꼭 가야돼
No, I want to.
You promise me
you're gonna go see the doctor.
안녕!
Good-bye.
몸 조심해
You take care.
당신도요
You too.
Shit.
봐라봐! 스파게티에
고기까지 들었어
Look what I got.
Look what I got for you here?
A little spaghetti and meat sauce.
That's it, buddy.
이태리인이라 착각 말고
잘 먹어, 잘지내라
We'll make an Italian out of you yet.
That's a good boy.
All right.
Have a good one.
What are you doing here?
It's 8:00 a.m.
어머, 여덟신데 벌써?
법정 출두가 두시인데
큰일났다구
I'm in the shitter, Martha. I gotta be
in court by 2:00 and I'm really behind.
모든 약속 취소하고, 드림머씨
안심시켜, 두시까지 간다고
Do me a favor. Cancel everything
and call Drimmer. Tell him we're fine.
- I'll be there by 2:00.
- At 2:00? Okay.
두시요? 네
Good morning, Martha.
미안, 굿모닝!
- Daddy!
- Hey, honey! Oh, God, I missed you.
아빠!
귀염둥이, 보고 싶었다!
We had a great time. We went for a walk
with Grandpa and saw rabbits.
너무 신났어요
놀다가 토끼도 보고…
천천히 말해
못 알아 듣겠어
Well, good. Why don't you slow down.
I can't understand a word you're saying.
아빠, 토끼 사줘요
- Daddy, I want a rabbit.
- I know you do, honey.
- Hi, darling. How are you?
- Good.
여보, 보고 싶었어
Oh, God, I missed you.
거짓말
Liar.
I did.
정말이야
자주 가버릴까봐
I should go away more often.
요건 내꺼
- I did this one.
- You did?
딴거 집어봐
- Pick another one.
- I thought it was this row you picked.
이게 내 카드 아냐?
아냐, 이거지
- It was this one.
- I think you're in a lot of trouble.
넌, 문제가 많어
Phooey. I can't do it.
Now pick a card, Dad.
아빠, 다시 뽑아
아무거나?
Any card at all?
누가 가르쳐 줬지?
- Of course.
- Where'd she learn this?
할아버지요
Grandpa showed me.
It's a surprise.
So, how was it?
집은 어땠어?
Come on. I'm a big boy.
I can take it.
어서 말해봐, 화 안낼게
It had a place for rabbits.
토끼도 키울수 있어요
뭐? 토, 토끼라구?
Oh, no! She said it.
She said the "R" word.
Not rabbits? Rabbits?
토끼는 아니겠지?
토끼요!
- 토끼!
한마디로…
너무 멋진 집이에요
Well, what can I tell you?
It's absolutely perfect.
이 줄에서?
In this row?
아니
언제쯤 집을 볼래요?
꼭 안사도 되니까…
So, when are you gonna come up
and take a look at it?
- Just for the hell of it?
- In this row?
내일 아침 어때?
How about tomorrow morning?
- Daddy, which row?
- You mean it?
정말이요?
If you can get me back
to the office by 1:00, yeah.
한시 이전에
날 풀어준다면…
아빠 어떤 줄?
Which row, Dad?
이줄에 있어
It's in this row, sweetheart.
여보, 여기좀 와봐요
Honey?
Honey, come here.
I want you to see this.
Well?
Well, it's... it's okay.
그저 그렇군
그저 그렇다구요?
너무 멋져요!
What do you mean?
It's fantastic.
멋져! 최고야!
It's great.
Just think of all the money
we're gonna save not living in New York.
뉴욕에 살 때보다
돈이 덜 들 거예요
The local high school is excellent.
My own children went there.
학교도 좋아요
우리 얘들도 다녔죠
얘들에겐 그만인 곳이죠
- You see?
- This is a terrific area for kids.
I'm sure it is.
Is it okay if I go upstairs?
그렇겠죠, 잠깐 올라가도?
올라가 보세요
여기서 기다리죠
- Go ahead. I'll wait for you down here.
- Thank you.
You know,
we still gotta decorate.
실내장식도 해야하니…
We can fix up anything.
We can have painting parties.
할수 있어요
친구를 부를께요
Painting parties?
Beth, you're making me very nervous.
칠을 하려구?
누굴 죽이려구?
이것봐, 너무 멋있어
Now look at this.
This is fantastic.
This would make a terrific playroom.
놀이방으로 좋겠어요
무슨 소리? 내 서재야
What are you talking about playroom?
This is my den. It's a den.
I knew you were gonna like it.
좋아할 줄 알았어요
I like it.
법원에 가네
I'll be in court.
How you doing, Dan?
Hi, Eunice.
Did Martha get back from lunch?
마사 들어왔나?
방금 들어왔어요
- She just returned.
- Thank you.
방해가 안되는지요
근처에 온 김에…
This isn't a bad time, is it?
I was in the area.
괜찮아요, 들어오시지
No. No. You...
Do you wanna come in my office?
계속있을거지? 잠깐!
You gonna be in your office later?
There's a little something... Excuse me.
- 어디서 뵜더라?
- 처음인데요
- Haven't we met somewhere?
- I don't think so.
She looked at me first.
날, 유혹하더니
앉아요
Sit down.
- 이젠 괜찮소?
- 좋아요
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
I was gonna call you today.
사실, 전화걸려고 했어요
너무 부끄러웠어요
그저…
This is terribly embarrassing.
I just wanted to say sorry
for what happened.
사과하려구 왔어요
너무 부담을 드렸어요
I had no right
to put you through that.
잊어버려요
Nothing happened, okay?
불안이 계속 쌓여서 터졌죠
I was going through a bad time
and everything was coming to a crisis.
이젠 안정됐어요, 고마워요
But I'm fine. I'm really all right.
And thank you.
고마울것 없어요
- You don't have to thank me.
- Oh, yeah, I do.
딴 사람이라면 도망갔겠죠
A lot of guys
would have just run away.
당신이 없었다면
큰일 날뻔 했어요
I don't know what I would have done
if you hadn't been there.
이젠 좋아보여요
멋진데요
Well, you... you look good.
As a matter of fact,
you look great.
Thanks.
So that's past?
그렇군요
- 부탁하나 더 할까요?
- 뭐죠?
- May I ask you one more favor?
- What's that?
I've got two tickets
to Madame Butterfly...
"나비부인" 표를 구했어요
two weeks from Thursday.
보름후인데
꼭 같이 가고 싶어요
화해의 계기랄까…
I'd really love it if you'd come
with me, kind of as a peace offering.
생각해줘서 고맙소
That's... That's very nice of you...
but I don't think it's a good idea.
- 하지만, 그러지 맙시다
- 부담 갖지 마세요
No strings attached.
알렉스!
변명도 마시고
그저, 물어본거예요
You don't have to explain.
I just thought I'd ask.
언젠가는…
So...
만날때가 있겠죠
I'll see you around sometime.
Come here.
Take care.
잘가요
Good-bye.
안녕히
Let's go, pal!
We're on a roll.
I like it.
Very nice.
That is no good.
How about Rodgers
versus whatchamacallit?
"로져스" 와 뭐라든가…
"위니츠키"
- Winitsky.
- Right. I got your memo.
맞아, 메모 봤어
- You gonna go for summary judgment?
- Why not, Arthur?
즉심판결을 받겠다고?
당연하지, 로져스가
그 내용을 읽었대요
The facts are not in dispute. Rodgers
admits reading Winitsky's article.
요점은, 그 내용을
인용했느냐는 거죠
The question is whether
he plagiarized it in his book.
You can't copyright an idea,
only the expression of the idea...
표현은 특허가 가능하지만
로져스가 표절안한건
명백해요
and Rodgers sure as hell didn't use
any of the words in the book.
Let me think about it.
연구해볼게
So, I hear you're about
to become a suburbanite.
시골로 이사한다지?
그러기로 했습니다
We're gonna take the big plunge.
- Got a buyer for the apartment?
- No.
- 아파트는 팔았나?
- 아뇨
집 마련에 애먹어도
- Got cold sweats about your escrow?
- Yeah.
이 소송은 문제 없겠지?
But not about Rodgers
versus Winitsky?
- No, sir.
- Good.
문제 없어요
아직도 회의 중이세요
He's still in a meeting.
곧 끝날줄 알았거든요
Yes, I know. I did expect him
to be through by now.
화요일에 나하구 점심먹자구
I'd like you to have lunch with me
on Tuesday, if you're around.
정말 고맙습니다
일정표를 볼게요
Thank you, Arthur. That'd be great.
Let me just check my diary.
메모를 남겨놨어요
You are on his list of calls.
It's Alex Forest.
알렉스에요
Again? I thought you told her
I'd call her back.
또? 전화해 준다고
말했을 텐데?!
알았어, 대기시켜
- I did.
- Put her on hold.
Would you mind holding?
기다리세요
화요일 좋습니다
- Tuesday would be great.
- I look forward to it.
기대하겠네
Thank you. I will too.
Put her through.
바꿔줘
Look, Alex, I thought we agreed
this was not a good idea.
알렉스!
이러지 않기로 했잖아
왜지?
Why?
미안해, 유혹한게
나라면 사과할게
I'm sorry.
I thought you understood.
If I misled you in some way,
I apologize.
But I don't think it's a good idea
if we talk to each other anymore.
그러니, 더 이상
말할 필요가 없어!
Okay?
Good-bye.
If she calls again,
tell her I'm not here.
또 전화하면
없다고 해줘
Thank you.
잠깐, 가만있어
당신을 쳐다보게
Wait. Let me do something.
Let me just look at you.
당신 아름다워
무척 아름다워
You're so beautiful.
You're just so beautiful.
엉큼한 사람!
- Wouldn't you know.
- I know.
관계중에 부상이 많대
Do you know how many injuries can...
겁주지 말아요!
- That's my wife!
- Don't terrorize them.
I'm a lawyer. I'm insured.
난, 보험든 변호사야
Oh, it's excited.
Now don't forget who gave you this.
내 덕인줄 알아요!
My cold sores are almost gone.
자, 부인들을 위해!
조심해야돼
This is for you. Ladies first.
I use that term advisedly.
You bet, sweetie.
그건, 내 마누라야
잘 들어봐
That's my wife!
A little attention, please.
Ladies. Gentleman.
- 내 마누란, 속박자요
- 당연하죠!
My wife.
My little ball and chain.
- You should have such a ball and chain.
- Mother of some of my children.
- 애들의 엄마죠
- 못나게 큰소린…
- Wouldn't be that confident about it.
- Here is to Miller, Goodman...
우리 회사를 위해
겔리거 사장님께!
Hurst and Gallagher.
비꼬지마! 단지
점심 초대를 받았을뿐이야
- Here's to Mrs. Gallagher.
- Give me a break, will you, guys?
All he did was ask me to lunch.
하긴, 전원주택에서
우릴 쳐다나 보겠수?
Your moving to your country estate.
You'll forget you ever knew us.
너무한데?
이럴때 책이 필요해
Wait a minute.
I read one of those self-help books.
그회사에서 출판한거 말이지
Published by Robbins and Hart,
of course.
물론, "무사생존법"
Samurai Self-Help.
그책에 친구와의
갈등해소도 써있어
In it, it tells you how to deal
with the anxieties of your friends...
as you move up the corporate ladder
and they stay put...
승진할 때도 조심해야되고
거꾸로 떨어질 때도…
or, God forbid, go down.
And in this book, it tells you
not to coddle your friends' anxieties.
친구를 무시하면 안된대
그러니 거짓말은 빼놓자구
So I'm not gonna make
any false reassurances, guys.
앞으론, 이렇게 만날수가 없어
세상이 바뀌었어
I'm not gonna tell you you're gonna be
up to the house every weekend.
Let's face it. Things have changed.
This is not a classless society.
너희같은 인간들과는
끝장이야
As a matter of fact, this is it.
Good-bye. Good-bye.
그말 할 줄 알았어
I knew he was gonna say that.
The man is running true to form.
본성이 드러났어
Honey, I think we gotta make
a clean break.
여보, 물오를 때 밀고 나가야지
헌친구들은 차버리고…
We're on a roll.
We gotta travel light.
참 잘놀았어, 고마워
Thanks for the time you've given us.
Here, you, drink. I want you
with a lamp shade on your head by 10:00.
이것 마시고, 열시에
한탕 뛸 준비해
오늘밤엔 웬일이야?
Why should today be any different
from any other?
Here's to you.
리차드씨
너무 늦은거 아뇨?
Yeah, Richards.
It's kind of late, isn't it?
사무실 전화가 안되니
이럴 수밖에 없어
If you refuse to take my phone calls
at the office, you leave me no choice.
새벽 두시나 됐는데
아침에 하면 안돼요?
It's 2:00 in the morning.
Can't this wait till tomorrow morning?
흥, 말하기 거북하지?
Is it awkward for you to talk?
그건 그래요
You could say that.
꼭 만나겠어
I've gotta see you.
제가 지금 서류가 없으니
내일 사무실에서 전화하죠
I don't have the...
the documentation to answer that right
now, but I'll call you from the office.
안돼! 내일 출판사
앞으로 나와!
No. Meet me in front of the Robbins
and Hart building tomorrow, 6:00.
여섯시! 실망시키지마!
Don't disappoint me.
Be there.
이걸로서 끝장이야!
- This has gotta stop.
- If you saw me, I wouldn't call.
만나만 주면 그런전화 안해요
아직도 몰라? 끝이야
우린 상관 없다구
Do you get it? It's over.
There's nothing between us.
실컷 재미보구나서
뭐 어쨌다구요?
You mean you've had your fun.
Now you just want a quiet life.
- Why are you doing this?
- Doing what?
왜 날 괴롭혀?
미친거 아냐?
- You need help.
- Don't tell me what I need.
정신 병원에 가야돼
You need a shrink!
왜 날 미워해요?
난 적이 아니에요
Why are you so hostile?
I'm not your enemy.
그런데 왜 날 괴롭혀?
- Then why are you trying to hurt me?
- I'm not. I love you.
해칠 생각은 없어요
사랑하니까
뭐라고?
- You what?
- I love you.
날 알지도 못하면서?
- You don't even know me.
- How can you say that?
그게 말이 되요?
주말에 잔 것뿐이야
그 이상 없어
We spent a weekend together,
that's all.
그 다음날은요?
싫었으면 왔겠어요?
You stayed that second night.
You must like me a little.
걱정됐으니까, 젠장
왜 이리 매달려?
Because I was concerned about you.
Why do you read so much into everything?
이해가 안돼
난, 임자가 있는 몸이야
Can't you understand? I have
a whole relationship with someone else.
I am very happy.
임자가 있다구요? 그런 사람이
왜 날 건드렸죠?
Whole means complete.
If your life's so damn complete,
what were you doing with me?
이런 식으로 따져?
사랑한답시구?
- Is that what you wanna talk about?
- I'm pregnant.
저, 임신했어요
산부인과에 갔었어요
I saw my gynecologist on Monday.
이 명함으로 확인해보세요
Here's his card.
You can call him.
You don't...
피임약을 썼냐구?
Use anything?
작년에 유산했기에
다시 임신 못할줄 알았어요
I had a very bad miscarriage last year.
I didn't think I could get pregnant.
내 앤지 어떻게 알아?
How do you know it's mine?
난 헤픈 여자가 아니에요
Because I don't sleep around.
미안해, 사과하지
I apologize.
정말 미안해, 걱정마
I'm sorry.
Don't worry. You're not gonna
have to handle this alone.
- 혼자 처리는 안시켜
- 처리라뇨?
Handle what?
유산말이야
수술비는 내가 낼게
The abortion. I'll take care of it.
I'll pay for it.
누가 유산시킨데요?
What makes you think
I want an abortion?
낳겠다는 심산이야?
You're not gonna have the baby.
물론, 이혼의 위험이 없는
편모 가정을 만들 거예요
Why not?
There are plenty
of one-parent families.
- At least they don't end in divorce.
- I don't have a say in this?
난, 결정권이 없나?
난, 애길 원해요
당신하곤 관계없어요
I want this child.
It has nothing to do with you. I want it
whether you're a part of it or not.
당신이 뭐라해도 낳을 거예요
Then why are you telling me?
Why not just go ahead and do it?
그럼 왜 말하는거야?
가서 낳으면 되지
당신이 기뻐하길 바랬어요
I was hoping that you would want
to be a part of it.
미친짓이야, 미쳤다구
This is crazy.
This is totally insane.
I'm 36 years old. It may be
my last chance to have a child.
전 36세에요, 애기는
이게 마지막기회예요
앞뒤를 보고 얘기해
Just think what you're saying.
잘 생각해봐
Just think about it.
우린 평생 신경을 써야돼
We are gonna live with this
for the rest of our lives.
I know that.
알고 있어요, 당신 기분도
알아요, 큰 경사니까
I've thought of that.
I know how you feel.
It's a big thing,
but it doesn't have to be a problem.
문제될게 뭐가 있어요?
걱정마세요
Really, it doesn't.
나한테 잘해주시면
저도 잘할게요
You play fair with me,
I'll play fair with you.
그는 애들을
벽장에 밀어넣었고
"He led Agnes and Nellie
into the hall closet and shut the door.
애들은 킬킬거리고
웃고 있었어요
Agnes and Nellie and Oink giggled
and laughed in the dark.
펄은 밖에서 두리번거리는데
Pearl listened outside the door.
'Oh, it works, ' cried Nellie.
아그네가 말하길
개가 날아간다
'Of course, ' said Oink.
'Look at the flying dog, '
yelled Agnes.
'Wow! ' cried Nellie.
넬리는 멍멍하고
펄은 꺽하고 하품했어
Pearl frowned. 'Who cares
about flying dogs? ' she said.
아그네가 "지렁이가
날아온다" 하자
Nobody heard her.
'Look out for the worms! '
squealed Agnes.
'Eeek! ' yelled Nellie
and Agnes together.
꽥하고 둘이 소리쳤어요
'Look at the monster cockroach! '
yelled Oink.
옹크고 놀래서
사람살려
'Help!"'
(초기 임신 감별약)
(1958년 스탠리 포레스트)
(사망-교육자, 사회사업가)
그래서 말이야
So you know what I did?
I called the doctor.
의사에게 전화했더니
축하한다는거야
You know what he says?
"Congratulations."
I can't even imagine
what she told him.
그게 뭐라 지껄였는지
상상하고도 남아
Anyway, that's not the end of it.
좌우지간, 거기서 끝난게 아냐
After I talk to the doctor...
속이 타서 오늘 아침에
아파트에 침입했어
this morning
I broke into her apartment.
I know. Me, a lawyer,
breaking and entering.
난 변호사지만
가릴때가 아니잖아
I'm looking for something, anything to
get a handle on what I'm dealing with.
뭐든지 꼬투리를 잡으려고
뛰어든거야
I thought maybe I could find out
she was sleeping with somebody else.
딴 남자의 증거라도 잡으려구
헌데 아무것도 없더라구
Well, I didn't find anything.
단서를 못잡을거야
가정법을 모르니까 미치겠어
Anyway, I didn't find anything.
Jimmy, I don't know anything
about family law.
You gotta help me.
What kind of case does she really have?
네가 도와줘야 되겠어
얼마나 불리하냐?
아주 불리해!
It ain't good.
그게 매일 전화해
She keeps calling the apartment.
내 처가 받으면 끊고 말야
Every time Beth answers the phone,
she hangs up.
I'm scared, Jimmy. I...
아주 으시시해
I don't wanna lose my family.
난 가정을 잃을까 겁이 나
무서운 사실입니다
The facts, as alleged,
are horrendous.
사용했던 무기는
전류발사기거나
The instrument allegedly used
in all three cases...
was an electronic shock device
or stun gun...
뉴욕경찰이 쓰는
가스총입니다
이총은 근육수축을 촉진시켜
몸을 뒤틀리게 합니다
부상위험은 더 있지만
곤봉보다는 좋다는 겁니다
Operator. May I help you?
아까부터 555-8129를
걸려하는데
Operator, I've been trying
to get 555-8129. 212?
통화정지 녹음이 나와요
- Recording says it's been disconnected.
- Just a moment, please.
미안해요, 비밀번호로
바뀌었어요
I'm sorry, the number's been
changed to an unlisted number.
비상이에요
번호를 알려줘요!
Operator, this is a real emergency.
You need to give me that number.
규칙에 안되게 되있어요
I'm sorry. We're not allowed
to give out that information.
미친놈!
- Well, fuck you!
- My place or yours?
맘에 꼭 들어요
우리도 정이 들었어요
- I like it. I like it a lot.
- Well, we've been very happy here.
너무 깨끗해요
사도록 노력하죠
I'd definitely like
to think about it, if I could.
1주일에 두 번씩
가정부가 오거든요
- It's so clean.
- Yes.
We have a cleaning lady who comes in
a couple times a week.
그 여자 번호를 드릴게요
- I can certainly give you her name.
- I'd love that.
애보는 여자것도
And there's baby-sitters galore.
The whole works.
Whatever information you would need.
You know, they have...
필요한 것은 몽땅 적어놨어요
모두 알려드리죠
여보, 이분은 알렉스예요
Hi, darling.
Darling, this is Alex.
미안해요
성이 뭐라시드라…
- I've forgotten your last name.
- Alex Forest.
알렉스 포레스트
제 남편 댄이에요
만나서 반가워요
Hi. Glad to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
반갑소
Haven't we met somewhere before?
어디서 뵌 것 같은데요?
I don't think so, no.
그럴 리가 없소, 전혀
아니에요, 만났어요, 요전에
일본파티에 오셨잖아요?
We have.
Weren't you at that party...
at the Japanese place
a few weeks ago?
Honey, the exercise book.
여보, 책파티 말이에요
그렇군
Oh, yeah.
You're a lawyer and you work
for the firm of...
당신은 변호사구
어느 회사시더라…
기억이 안나지만
여하튼, 만났어요
What's the name?
Well, anyway, we've definitely met.
Well, you have a good memory.
기억력이 좋으시군
I never forget a face.
얼굴은 안잊어요
세상 좁아요
It's a small world.
It certainly is.
참, 시골로 가신다구요?
So, I gather
you're going to the country?
- Moving to the country?
- Yes.
이사하신다며?
- Have you found a place yet?
- We found a place in Bedford.
집을 사셨나요?
실은 베드포드에 샀어요
가보셨어요?
- Do you know it up there?
- Oh, it's beautiful, yes.
아름다운 곳이에요
곧 이사하실 예정이군요?
I guess you'll be moving
out of here almost immediately?
우선 내부수리를 하고요
당장 계실곳이 필요하겠군요?
Actually, we wanted to do
some remodeling first.
I guess you're looking for a place
right away, aren't you?
네, 빨리 안정하고 싶어요
Well, yeah,
I'd kind of like to settle in.
Alex is expecting a baby.
알렉스는 애기 가졌대요
Oh, that's...
할 일이 있어서
먼저 실례하오
Will you excuse me?
I have some work I've got to do.
I better run too.
저도 가야 돼요
Thank you for the tea
and showing me the apartment.
보여줘서 감사해요
- You're very welcome.
- I like it.
언제든지 오세요
좋아요, 아주 좋아요
- I really like it.
- We've been very happy here.
우리도 정들었어요
I'd like to think about it,
if I could.
사도록 해볼게요
직통번호예요
언제든지 거세요
Let me give you our number
so you can call us direct.
Thank you.
- I'll keep in touch.
- Great.
전화 걸게요
- Bye-bye.
- Good-bye.
She seemed really interested.
정말 사고 싶은가봐요
It's funny.
She didn't mention a husband.
이상해요, 남편얘길 안해요
혼잔가 보죠?
I get the feeling
that she's on her own.
- What is it? You seem down.
- No, I'm just tired.
- 왜 그래요? 우울하시니?
- 아냐, 좀 피곤해서
- Hello?
- Hi, it's me.
나야!
Who?
누구?
You know damn well who it is.
Let me in. I wanna talk.
시침떼지마, 할말이 있어
이제 할말있다구?
So now you wanna talk?
So, what can I get you?
I've got scotch, vodka.
뭘 드실까?
스캇치, 보드카 어떤걸?
- I've got a nice chablis...
- Cut the shit, will you?
집어쳐! 알겠어?
Just cut it!
집어치라구!
I don't know what you're up to...
어떤 흉계든
지금 당장 그만둬!
but I'm gonna tell you
it's gonna stop right now.
No, it's not gonna stop.
It's gonna go on and on...
못끝내, 계속 골탕먹일거야
책임회피를 안할때까지…
until you face up
to your responsibilities.
What responsibilities?
무슨 책임?
I'm pregnant.
I'm going to have our child.
임신했잖아?
우리 애란 말야
네가 선택한거지
나완 상관없어
That's your choice, honey.
That has nothing to do with me.
I just wanna be
a part of your life.
난, 조금이나마 너의
일부가 되고픈거야
뭐야? 그래서 내 아파트에
왔던거야?
This is the way you do it, huh?
Showing up at my apartment?
What am I supposed to do?
You won't answer my calls.
그럼 어떻게 해? 전화는
안받고 번호도 바꿨구
You change your number.
I'm not going to be ignored!
따돌림을 당할 수는 없어
You don't get it.
You just... You don't get it.
모르는군, 아직도
무슨 뜻인지 몰라
Don't you remember our weekend?
주말일 생각 안나?
사실, 너무 멋졌어
I mean, wasn't that wonderful?
왜 그때처럼
달콤하지 못해?
Why can't we just
be like that again?
I know you feel it too.
I mean, what are you so afraid of?
너도 좋았잖아
그걸 왜 부정해?
Hey, don't flatter yourself.
야, 야, 기분내지마!
때려! 해줄 자신없으면
때려나 줘!
Go ahead, hit me.
If you can't fuck me, just hit me.
알렉스, 넌 비참해졌어
쓸쓸하고 측은해
You're so sad. Do you know that?
You're lonely and very sad.
네가 날 동정해?
Don't you ever pity me,
you smug bastard.
불쌍하다, 불쌍해
넌, 미친년이야
I'll pity you,
because you're sick.
왜? 네가 나를
갈보취급 못하게 해서?
Why? Because I won't allow you
to treat me like some slut...
you can just bang a couple times
and throw in the garbage?
두어번 주무르고
쓰레기통에 쳐넣기냐?
난, 네 아기의 엄마야
조금은 존중해봐
I'm gonna be
the mother of your child.
I want a little respect.
You want respect?
존중을 바래?
- Respect.
- What are you doing?
뭣하는 거야?
제발 가지마? 댄!
본심이 아냐, 미안해
Please don't go.
I didn't mean it. I'm sorry.
I'll tell your wife.
네 처에게 말할거야
말해봐, 죽일거야
You tell my wife, I'll kill you.
It only takes a phone call!
전화 못할까봐!
Hello? Hello?
Guys, that's on the second door
to the left all the way in the landing.
왼쪽 둘째문으로 가세요
Thank you.
왜 벌써 도착했니?
You could have stayed
in the apartment.
댄이 어찌나 서두르는지
이거, 엄마 아니에요?
Dan was in such a hurry
to get out of New York.
Mama, that's you, isn't it?
Oh, Lord, put it away.
에그, 치워라
All right, easy on that door frame.
Nice, nice.
Just like a glove.
I got it. Sorry.
내가 받을게
여보세요?
Hello? Martha.
마사!
마사 전화야
It's Martha.
여보세요?
여보, 기분어때?
하수공 왔었어?
Hi, honey. How you doing?
Did the plumber come yet?
Did he ever.
왔었죠
가격 말하지마
입맛 떨어져
I don't really wanna know about it.
Guess what I'm looking at.
여보, 내가 지금
뭘 보고 있는지 알아?
- You got it?
- Yeah, I got it right here.
구했어요?
아무렴, 글쎄 암놈인 것 같애
Or I should say, I got her.
What's she like?
이뻐요?
Well, she's cute.
She looks like a rabbit.
이뻐, 토끼같이 생겼어
She's white, long ears,
little pink eyes.
백색에다, 귀크고
눈이 빨간데
이쁜 모양이군요
엘렌은 모르고 있겠지?
Ellen doesn't know
anything about it?
몰라, 기대도 않고 있어요
No, she doesn't think
she's gonna get one.
오래 일하면 별 것 다 보게 돼
See what happens if
you work here too long, Eunice?
- Isn't she cute.
- Thank you.
이쁘네요
Oh, I forgot.
This arrived for you.
참, 이게 왔어요
- Good night, Eunice.
- Good night, Mr. Gallagher.
Hey, Joaquin!
Jesus fucking Christ!
이런, 젠장!
Fucking bitch!
Jesus Christ.
나쁜년!
아냐, 전기고장 같애
그냥 타버리더군
It had something to do
with the electrical system.
The whole goddamn thing blew up.
A lot of smoke.
All right, honey,
I'll see you in a little while.
알겠어 여보! 조심할게
(렌트카)
서류 잊었어요, 겔리거씨
Mr. Gallagher?
You forgot your contract.
(들어봐-알렉스)
댄, 안녕! 놀랐어?
Hello, Dan.
Are you surprised?
너 때문에 이지경이 됐어
This is what you've reduced me to.
가볍게 끝날줄 알았지?
안돼!
I guess you thought
you'd get away with it.
Well, you can't.
Because part of you
is growing inside of me...
너의 일부분이
네몸에서 자라고 있어
and that's a fact, Dan,
and you'd better start...
그 엄숙한 사실을
겸손히 받아들여
learning how to deal with it.
왜냐하면, 난 널 느끼고
'Cause, you know, I feel you.
음미하구, 생각해
I taste you.
I think you.
또, 어루만지구
I touch you.
알겠어? 아냐구?
Can you understand?
Can you?
I'm just asking you...
내가 바라는건
책임을 인정하라는거야
to acknowledge
your responsibilities.
그게 잘못됐나?
Is that so bad?
I don't think so.
절대 잘못된게 아냐
부당하지 않다구
I don't think it's unreasonable.
그리구, 또하나는
네 생각엔
And, you know,
another thing is that...
you thought you could just
walk into my life...
내 인생에 걸어 들어와
뒤집어 엎어놓고
and turn it upside down...
without a thought
for anyone but yourself.
훌쩍 떠나면 될 줄 알았겠지
넌, 어떤놈인지 알아?
넌 개자식이야
You know what you are, Dan?
You're a cock-sucking
son of a bitch.
널 증오해!
I hate you. I bet
you don't even like girls, do you?
넌 계집맛도 모르는 놈이야
병신, 내시야!
You flaming, fucking faggot.
Daddy! Thank you!
아빠, 고마워요
천만에, 좋으니?
Like it?
내 인생에 걸어 들어와서
You thought you could just
walk into my life...
and turn it upside down...
뒤집어 엎어놓고 훌쩍 떠나면
될줄 알았겠지
without a thought
for anyone but yourself.
You know what you are, Dan?
넌, 어떤놈인지 알아?
넌 개자식이야!
You're a cock-sucking
son of a bitch.
넌 계집맛도 모르지?
You are.
I bet you don't
even like girls, do you?
They probably scare you.
여자가 무섭겠지
I know I do.
그러니 내가 무섭지?
So you're scared of me, aren't you?
무서워서 오금이
저리지? 겁쟁이
You're fucking frightened of me.
You're afraid.
You're afraid, aren't you?
You gutless, heartless...
겁쟁이, 배짱없고
비정하고, 뼈대없는
spineless fucking son of a bitch.
천하의 개새끼
너 각오해!
I hate you.
You deserve everything you get...
Sorry.
I was wondering what you
were doing up so late.
놀래켜서 미안해요
늦게 일하길래
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to scare you.
아니, 괜찮아
변론진술을 듣느라고
It's okay. I was just listening
to a deposition and couldn't sleep.
Come on.
I'm gonna give you a back rub.
이리와요
안마해 드릴게
- A back rub?
- Brandy, a back rub.
브랜디에 안마면
잠이 절로 와요
You won't know what hit you.
브랜디라, 좋지
Sounds good.
제 의뢰인의 말은
My client wants it stopped.
더 이상 당하고 싶지
않다는 겁니다
Hejust wants an end
to the harassment.
He's positive it was this woman
who trashed the car?
차를 부순건 그녀가
확실하다는 겁니까?
- 네, 그렇습니다
- 증인은?
Yes, of course.
- Any witnesses?
- No.
He's welcome to file a complaint,
if it'd make him feel better.
고발장을 내시죠
증거가 없어 문제지만
There's not a lot you can do
without proof.
Look, Lieutenant, this woman
is completely irrational.
경위님, 이 여자는
완전히 미친 여자에요
There's no telling
what she could do.
예측 못합니다
We can't go around arresting people
for what they might do. You know that.
예측만 갖고
구속 할순 없잖소
I'm not asking you to arrest her.
He simply...
구속하라는게 아니라
그분은 단지…
He wants her warned.
경고를 부탁하는 거죠
Well, we could talk to her.
경고를 하게되면
공식화됩니다
It may make things public.
He's not gonna like that.
그분도 창피할거고
It may even aggravate
the situation with the girl.
그녀와의 관계가
악화 될수도 있죠
왜요?
How's that?
만약 그런일로 여자의
기분이 풀렸다면
Whatever resentment she's feeling,
she probably got it out of her system.
And any action we take
could provoke her.
또 건드리면 화 안낼까요?
What if she didn't get it
out of her system? What then?
기분이 안풀렸다고
가정한다면?
You have to catch her in the act.
Then we can bring charges.
범행현장에서 구속 해야죠
Well, you say he just has to
sit there and take it?
그러면 그분으로선
딴 방법이 없군요?
It's his bed. Afraid
he's gonna have to lie in it.
파놓은 무덤인데
어떡합니까?
Come on.
Come on, Ellen.
We're going to Grandma's.
엘렌, 할머니 집에 가자
Come on, Quince.
Quincy, come on. Hurry up.
빨리와, 퀸씨
Come on. Get on in.
Hurry up.
빨리 들어가!
Watch his tail, sweetie.
Make him sit down.
꼬리 끼겠다
조심해라
차를 아직 못고쳤군?
See you didn't get your car back.
No, it's a total write-off.
The electrical system's just shot.
폐차 시켰어요
전기가 엉망이래요
Extraordinary, those foreign cars.
외국 차는 바가지야
- Here you are, dear.
- Oh, thank you.
- Wanna try again, sweetie?
- Okay.
다시해보렴
Okay. So?
Dear Priscilla, Miles asked me
to ask you to marry him.
프리실라양, 마일즈가
저보고 청혼해 달랍니다
Very good.
다시한번 해보자
You wanna do it one more time.
Do it with your hat and do the bow.
모자쓰고, 절하구
So when you actually do it,
you know what you're doing.
진짜하는 기분으로
해봐
Let me see your bow.
절부터 하고
And what do you say?
그럼, 대사는?
Dear Priscilla, Miles asked me
to ask you to marry him.
프리실라양. 마일즈씨가
청혼합니다
Very good.
됐어!
Come here.
That was good.
잘했어
- Thank you.
- That was really good.
That was so good.
너무 잘했어
사랑해!
- I love you.
- I love you too.
나도 사랑해요
Thank you, darling.
고맙다!
Come on, Quincy.
- 아빠
- 왜그래?
Daddy!
What?
화이티가 없어!
Whitey's gone!
It's all right, darling.
It's gonna be okay, sweetie.
이제 괜찮아
아가야, 안심해
You should try to get some sleep.
맘놓고 자거라
- She okay?
- She's asleep.
- 애는 괜찮어?
- 잠들었어요
- Did you call the police?
- Not yet, no.
- 경찰을 불렀어요?
- 아직 안했어
Why not?
왜요?
Honey, we gotta talk.
여보, 할말이 있어
What is it?
뭔데요?
I know who did this.
범인을 알아
You do?
당신이?
Who?
누군데?
Remember the girl who...
전에 찾아왔던
여자 생각나지?
came to the apartment?
The one I met
in the Japanese restaurant?
일본식당에서
만났던 여자말야
The one with the blond hair.
금발여자 말예요?
You're scaring me.
예감이 불길해요
What is it?
뭐예요?
그여자와 관계했어요?
Did you have an affair with her?
Yes.
I am so sorry.
미안해, 베스
The last thing I ever wanted to do
was to hurt you.
당신을 괴롭히는 일은
안하려고 했어
Are you in love with her?
그녀를 사랑하나요?
No, it was one night.
It didn't mean anything.
아냐, 그저 하룻밤만이었어
전혀 의미가 없었어
What has it got to do
with what's happened?
그것이 이런일들과…
무슨 상관이?
She's pregnant.
임신했어
She's... It's yours?
그녀가, 당신 애기를?
I don't know. That's what she says.
Honey, listen to me.
잘 모르겠어
그렇다는군
나가요, 나가!
이집에서 나가세요
Get out!
I want you out of here!
I want you out of this house,
and I want you out now!
지금 당장! 어떻게
그런 짓을! 미워요
How could you do this?
I hate you!
- Honey, you don't understand.
- I don't wanna hear it!
제발 들어요, 베스!
제발, 좀…
- I don't wanna hear it!
- Please, just listen to me.
듣기 싫어요, 듣기 싫어
진정해, 여보!
Please, please, listen.
어쩜 그럴 수 있어요?
What is the matter with you?
Dan. What a pleasant surprise.
댄, 천만 뜻밖이네요
It's over, Alex. It's all finished.
I told Beth. She knows all about it.
이제 끝났어, 끝났다구
베스에게 다 얘기했어
Sure.
You haven't got the balls.
쳇, 너따윈 말못해
Why don't you speak to her.
내 처와 통화해봐!
Why would I wanna talk to her?
내가 왜 그년하고
얘기해?
This is Beth Gallagher.
겔리거 부인예요
If you ever come near my family again,
I'll kill you. You understand?
또다시 우리집에 오면
널 죽일거야!
That's the last one.
I mean it.
그게 마지막 전화다
정말이야
여보세요? 아빠야?
Hello?
Hi, Daddy.
When are you coming home?
아빠, 언제 집에 와?
Honey, I don't know.
How are you doing?
나도 몰라, 아가야
넌 어떠니?
Good.
좋아
Grandpa taught me a new card trick.
할아버지가 새 요술을
배워줬어
Oh, did he?
The one with the jacks?
그래? 짹으로 하는거?
No, the one with kings.
아냐, 킹으루
Good.
뭐라고? 안할게
I won't.
Good.
How's Mommy?
Send her my love?
엄마는?
안부 전해줘!
Okay. Good-bye.
알았어, 안녕!
Daddy?
내일 전화해요
Call me tomorrow.
I will. I promise.
아무렴, 약속해
You be sure
you tell Mommy I called?
엄마한테 아빠전화였다고
말해라
I will.
그럴게
나두 아빠 사랑해
Love you a lot too.
Hi, Mrs. Gallagher.
Did you forget something?
뭘 잊으셨나요?
- I came to get Ellen.
- Ellen?
엘렌을 데리러 왔어요
엘렌요? 벌써
데려가셨잖아요?
I thought you picked her up already.
Well, I'm sure
she's left already.
확실히 떠났어요
베티야, 엘렌 봤어?
Betty, is Ellen in here with you?
간지가 오래 됐는데
- She's gone home already.
- Are you sure?
I'm positive. She's not inside
and she's not in the playground.
여기엔 없어요
데려가시지 않았어요?
- I thought you picked her up.
- Who did pick her up?
누가 데려갔어?
멀리 갔을라구
Don't worry.
She can't have gone far.
- You don't understand.
- I'll check her locker.
- 이건 심각해요
- 교실에 가볼게요
Alicia, where's Ellen?
알리사, 엘렌 봤어?
She's gone.
갔는데요
Call the police!
경찰을 부르세요
제발 무사했으면!
Please let her be all right.
Please.
Oh, Christ.
Where are you?
어디 갔니?
어디 있지?
- Bye-bye, Ellen.
- Bye.
뽀뽀해줘
Can I have a kiss?
Excuse me. I'm looking
for a patient named Gallagher.
겔리거 부인의 병실은?
남편입니다
I'm her husband.
복도맨끝, 22호실에
계십니다
Room 22 at the end of the corridor.
- Is she gonna be okay?
- Yeah, she'll be fine.
제 처가 괜찮겠죠?
안심해요, 행운이에요
큰일날뻔 했죠
She was very lucky.
It might've been a lot worse.
Thank you.
Hi, baby.
보고 싶었어, 별일없지?
Oh, God, I missed you.
I missed you, honey.
Are you okay?
Did you see Mommy yet?
엄마 봤어?
- Yeah.
- Oh, good.
You stay here with Granny.
I'm gonna go see Mommy.
할머니하고 있거라
엄마볼테니
You're gonna be okay.
괜찮을거라는군
I came in before.
I tried to explain the situation.
전에 말했잖소
모든 상황을 말이오
You didn't wanna listen to me.
Now, the woman took my kid.
내말 안들려요?
애를 데려갔으면 납치요
납치!
That's kidnapping, right?
Am I right?
My wife's in the hospital.
She could've been killed.
처는 입원했고
그런걸 가만놔둬요?
- If you're not gonna do something...
- Take it easy. You don't have to shout.
침착하슈
귀 안먹었소
좋소, 어쩔 작정이요?
Okay, what are you gonna do?
We'll tell New York to pick her up
and bring her in for questioning.
뉴욕에다 신고해서
불러드릴게요, 됐소?
알겠소, 그럼…
Okay, then I'm...
I'm gonna go to the hospital
tomorrow, pick my wife up.
내일가서
처를 퇴원시키겠소
And hopefully...
그리구 주말엔
집에 있을 것 같소
I'll be home for the weekend
if you need to talk to me.
연락주세요
Thank you, Lieutenant.
감사합니다
You're welcome.
천만에요
How's that feel?
Good and warm?
어때, 따뜻하지?
- You all cozy?
- Is Mommy gonna be all right?
포근하구?
엄마, 안아프지?
Mommy's gonna be fine, honey.
엄마는 곧 나을거야
She's gonna be fine.
Are you going to stay with us?
우리와 같이 있을거지?
I'm gonna stay with you, honey.
아가야, 같이있고 싶단다
Now, you go to sleep, okay?
자, 잠자렴
Good night, doll.
잘자, 아가씨
Forever?
정말 안가지?
I promise, honey.
약속하마
You mean the detectives in Manhattan
have no idea where she's gone?
아니, 그여자의
행방을 모른다구요?
They don't know where she is?
정말 모른단 말입니까?
No, I see.
알겠소
If you get any more information,
be sure and let me know, Lieutenant.
정보받는대로 꼭 알려주십시오
Thank you very much, sir.
Good night.
대단히 감사합니다
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
여기 있어
- How does the arm feel?
- It hurts.
팔은 어때?
아파요
I'll get you some more painkillers.
진통제를 더 줄까?
Thanks.
Now, you just holler if
you need anything else, all right?
필요하면 불러요
알겠지?
I'd love a cup of tea.
차를 마시고 싶어요
You got it.
끓일게
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭣하지?
Why are you here?
왜 여기 있냐구
He tried...
그분이 어젯밤 헤어지자더니
to say good-bye to me last night.
But he couldn't because...
못하더라구, 서로의 감정이
같은걸 느꼈거든
he and I feel
the same way about each other.
너도 알잖아?
두사람이 처음만나서
Do you know how it is when you
meet somebody for the first time?
And you get this instant attraction.
첫눈에 끌리는거 말야
And don't you think
I understand what you're doing?
그리구 내가 네 수작을
모를줄 알구?
You're trying to move him
into the country...
넌 그분을 시골로
빼돌릴려고 하지
and you're keeping him
away from me.
그리구 나를 떼어놓고선…
And you're playing happy family.
소꿉장난 하는거지
Aren't you?
안 그래?
You wouldn't understand that
because you're so selfish.
넌 이기주의자니까
이해 못해
그분이 네 얘길 많이 하더라
He told me about you.
그분은 순수했어
He was very honest.
If you weren't so stupid,
you'd know that.
바보 아니면 알거야
넌, 바보야
But you're so stupid.
You're a stupid, selfish bitch!
욕심쟁이, 바보년!
이 바보, 욕심쟁이…
댄!